Wheeler, C. S. (Charles Stearns), 1816-1843. C. S. (Charles Stearns) Wheeler correspondence (MS Am 1884.1): Guide.
C. S. (Charles Stearns) Wheeler correspondence,
1833-1843.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1884.1
Wheeler, C. S. (Charles Stearns), 1816-1843.
1 box (.5 linear ft.)
Letters to classics scholar C. S. Wheeler pertaining to personal and professional matters.
*72M-13. Gift of Mr. Kenneth W. Cameron, Trinity College Hartford 6, Connecticut; received: 1972 October 13.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material.
Wheeler, a classical scholar, was a tutor in Greek and an instructor in history at Harvard (1838-1842).
Organized into the following series:
I. Letter from Charles Stearns Wheeler
II. Letters to Charles Stearns Wheeler
III. Other papers
Primarily letters to Wheeler pertaining to both personal and professional matters.
- I. Letter from Charles Stearns Wheeler
  - Wheeler, Charles Stearns, 1816-1843. A.L.s. to Cornelius Conway Felton; [n.p., ca. 1843], (1); 1s. (4p.).
    Lacks beginning.
- II. Letters to Charles Stearns Wheeler
  - Adams, John Clark, d. 1874. 2 letters:, (2)
    A.L.s.; Clyde, 28 Feb 1840. 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Clyde, 22 Jun 1840. 1s. (4p.).
  - Allen, William, d. 1895. A.L.s.; Barnstable, 1 Jun 1839., (3); 1s. (3p.).
  - Bartlett, Robert. 2 letters:, (4)
    A.L.s.; Plymouth, 22 Feb [ca. 1841] 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Plymouth, 27 Jul 1842. 1s. (4p.).
  - Crafts, William Augustus, 1819-1906. A.L.s.; Boston, 6 Feb 1840., (5); 1s. (2p.).
  - Crystal [pseud.] A.L.s.; [n.p.] 17 Jul 1839., (6); 1s. (3p.).
  - Davis, William Augustus, d. 1898. 2 letters:, (7)
    A.L.s.; [n.p.] 10 Oct 1839. 1s. (3p.).
    A.L.s.; Springfield, 13 Nov 1842. 1s. (4p.).
  - Fairman, William. A.L.s.; Lancaster, 15 Aug 1841., (8); 1s. (3p.).
  - French, Henry, d. 1840. A.L.s.; Exeter, 22 Feb 1840., (9); 1s. (4p.).
  - Haskins, David Greene, 1818-1896. 2 letters:, (10)
    A.L.s.; Dorchester, 9 Sep 1840. 1s. (2p.).
    A.L.s.; Boston, 22 Jun 1841. 1s. (3p.).
  - Hildreth, Richard, 1807-1865. 6 letters:, (11)
    A.L.s.; New York, 17 Aug 1840. 1s. (3p.).
    A.L.s.; [Georgetown] Demerara, 27 Oct 1840. 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Georgetown, Demerara, 12 Nov 1840. 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Georgetown, Demerara, 27 Jan 1841. 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Demerara, 24 Mar 1841. 1s. (3p.).
    A.L.s.; Demerara, 24 May 1841. 1s. (4p.).
  - Howe, Sarah L. A.L.s.; [n.p., ca. Apr 1841], (12); 1s. (3p.).
  - Hubbard, Henry, d. 1876. 2 letters:, (13)
    A.L.s.; Charlestown, 19 Aug [ca. 1839] 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Worcester, 15 Feb 1840. 1s. (3p.).
  - Mackintosh, Robert James, b. 1806. A.L.s.; London, 3 May 1841., (14); 1s. (3p.).
    With envelope.
  - Morison, Horace, d. 1870. A.L.s.; Baltimore, 17 Oct 1838., (15); 1s. (4p.).
  - Munroe, James, and Co. 3 letters:, (16)
    A.L.s.; Boston, 10 Apr 1839. 1s. (2p.).
    A.L.s.; Boston, 19 Sep 1839. 1s. (2p.).
    A.L.s.; Boston, 19 Nov 1839. 1s. (2p.).
  - Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864. 3 letters:, (17)
    A.L.s.; [Cambridge] 23 Jun [ca. 1839] 1s. (2p.).
    A.L.s.; [Cambridge] 1 Feb 1840. 1s. (4p.). With a letter from Noah Fifield to Josiah Quincy; Weymouth, 31 Jan 1839.
    A.L.s.; [Cambridge] 28 Jan 1841. 1s. (2p.).
  - Richardson, James, 1817-1863. 3 letters:, (18)
    A.L.s.; Milford, 2 Nov 1838. 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; [Providence, ca. 1841 ] 1s. (2p.).
    A.L.s.; Medfield, 23 Jun 1842. 1s. (3p.).
  - Russell, Le Baron, d. 1889. A.L.s.; Boston, 28 Jul 1842., (19); 1s. (2p.).
  - Scates, Charles Woodman, d. 1873. A.L.s.; Edingsville, 6 Aug 1839., (20); 1s. (4p.).
  - Stearns, William L. A.L.s.; Maine, 27 Jun 1842., (21); 1s. (4p.).
  - Treat, Samuel, 1815-1902. 2 letters:, (22)
    A.L.s.; Genesco, 13 Jul [ca. 1840] 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Genesco, 17 Aug 1840. 1s. (4p.).
  - Weiss, John, 1818-1879. 2 letters:, (23)
    A.L.s.; Jamaica Plain, 29 Aug 1839. 1s. (2p.).
    A.L.s.; Jamaica Plain, 23 Oct 1839. 1s. (2p.).
  - Wheeler, William Francis. 3 letters:, (24)
    A.L.s.; Lincoln, 14 Oct 1842. 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Lincoln, 30 Dec 1842. 1s. (4p.).
    A.L.s.; Lincoln, 29 May 1843. 1s. (4p.).
- III. Other papers
  - Sewall, Charles Chauncy. A.L.s. to []; Medfield, 11 May [1843], (25); 1s. (4p.).
  - [Charles Stearns Wheeler's admission to Harvard]. MS.; [Cambridge] Jul 1833., (26); 1s. (2p.).
    Signed by Josiah Quincy.
  - [Bills for books bought by Charles Stearns Wheeler]. MS.; Boston, [1840], (27); 2s. (4p.).